Thomas Clarke Tel: 07757 075 683

Profile:

A degree in Computer Science is allowing me to explore my interests and fuel my passion for technology, from the theory of data structures to the workings of robots. I am task focused, have a positive attitude and an industrious work ethic, all of which are important for my degree and for the real world of work. I have had worked in several different working environments doing difference jobs, all of which are giving me new experiences to help build myself and prepare me for my future career. I can adapt to new environments quickly and deal with problems effectively, skills which I can apply in the technological world.

Qualifications:

Currently studying: University of Birmingham - BSc in Computer Science with a Year in Industry - September 2014 to July 2018

• 1st Year Results: Year average was 85%, with my top 3 scores being 88% (Information and the Web), 95% (Software Workshop) and 100% (Robot Programming)

John Cleveland College – September 2010 to August 2014

- A Levels: Mathematics (A*), Physics (A), ICT (A), AS History (C); Extended Project Qualification (A).
- GCSEs: 3 A*s, 6 As, 1 B and OCR Level 2 National Double Award in ICT (Distinction).

Work History:

- Software Developer, Majestic, July 2015 to September 2015: Using various web technologies and utilising D3.js, me and a team of 2 other developers are using the Majestic API to create data visualisations. The work can be seen at https://labs.majestic.com. I also represented Majestic at Leeds Hack 2015.
- Supervisor, Spar, March 2015 to present: Responsibilities include supervising sales assistants, opening and setting up the shop, handling money, maintaining some important systems and more of the shop in general and handling more customer queries.
- Sales Assistant, Spar (before promotion to supervisor listed above), October 2014 to March 2015: My responsibilities were serving customers, operating the tills and maintaining the shop interior.
- Software Tester, Crane Electronics Ltd., Summer 2014: Responsibilities involved exploring and testing a range of products to identify faults or problems and reporting them to the software engineer for revision. The main project was black box testing on an Android based device.
- Garden Centre Assistant, Woodlands Nursery & Garden Centre, October 2013 to January 2014: Responsibilities involved fast-paced customer service and till working.
- IT Department, Aston Martin, Warwick, July 2011: Responsibilities involved building new computers for the assembly line and installing them across the factory.

Achievements, Interests and Hobbies:

- Knowledge of how to program in Java, OCaml and web technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, D3.js, PHP).
- Attending various hackathons:
 - I represented Majestic at Leeds Hack 2015 (leedshack.org) as a sponsor, where I introduced Majestic to the attendees, was on hand to set hackers up with Majestic accounts, act as technical support and have discussions with them about what they

Thomas Clarke Tel: 07757 075 683

- could do as projects, and was responsible for selecting winner for our prizes and awarding them.
- BrumHack 2.0 where our team created a fast-paced fighting game in Unity using C# and having to create extra C# programs to run within the game to gather information about various websites using Majestic's API.
- Programming robots using LeJOS and scoring 100% in this robotics module.
- Some experience in Android Application Development, jQuery and Visual Basic.
- I have participated in extra circular activities including:
 - o an EPQ (Extended Project Qualification) based on creating an Android Application,
 - o a Silver Crest Award based on Astronomy,
 - o a v50 volunteering award,
- Member of the Computer Science Society and Games Development Society.
- Bass guitar (achieved Merit at Grade 3).
- Socialising, live music, game design and travelling.

Other Information:

- Home address: 60 Langdale Road, Hinckley, Leicestershire, LE10 ONS
- Term-time address: 31B Tiverton Rd, Birmingham, West Midlands, B29 6BW
- Email: tomclarke96@hotmail.co.uk
- LinkedIn profile: linkedin.com/in/tombclarke
- Website: tombclarke.co.uk
- Full, clean UK Driving Licence, with own car.
- D.O.B.: 04/03/199
- Non smoker

Reference:

- Majestic-12 Ltd:
 - o Steve Pitchford
 - o Tel: 07974963675
 - o Email: stevep@majesticseo.com
- Spar, Guild of Students, University of Birmingham:
 - o Callum Cue
 - o Tel: 07414540071
- Crane-Electronics Ltd:
 - o Neil McDonald
 - o Tel: 01455 251488
 - o Email: nmcdonald@crane-electronics.com